<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryan Tolboom</title>
    <link>https://using.tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ryan Tolboom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://using.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended Network Growth in jr - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://using.tech/posts/jr_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://using.tech/posts/jr_2/</guid>
      <description>Goal With the basics of the jr network established (see Introducing jr: A Peer-to-Peer Social Network), I wanted to simulate the growth of the extended network and find a mathematical model that describes this growth.
core/extended-network-test builds a test network of 100 nodes each following 10 random nodes. It then performs 1000 random syncs (two nodes chosen at random sync with each other) and records the average extended network size at each iteration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing jr: A Peer-to-Peer Social Network</title>
      <link>https://using.tech/posts/jr_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://using.tech/posts/jr_1/</guid>
      <description>Intro A friend of mine, John R., has been extolling the virtues of Clojure for years now. At one point, I bought Clojure for the Brave and True, read it, and implemented a few toy programs. It&#39;s an excellent book. Recently I found myself looking for a language to implement a project to measure analyze a Secure Scuttlebutt style social network. While trying to decide between Guile, Chicken Scheme, and Racket I remembered John&#39;s advice and instead went with Clojure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out Spacemacs</title>
      <link>https://using.tech/posts/spacemacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://using.tech/posts/spacemacs/</guid>
      <description>Intro In high school, I was given a Sun 3/60 workstation and given instructions to set everything up and learn how to use vi. &amp;ldquo;You&#39;ll never find a better editor&amp;rdquo; my boss told me. In retrospect, I think you&#39;ll never find a better editing concept, and that&#39;s modal editing.
Developers spend far more time reading than they do typing. Breaking reading and writing (or inserting) into two discrete modes seems natural after you take a moment to get used to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://using.tech/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://using.tech/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a father of two, living in New Jersey and working as a university lecturer. I&#39;ve been fortunate enough to work in several technological fields throughout my life with a significant amount of experience in the education realm. This site is meant to serve as a space to post information about what I&#39;m currently working on with the hope being that other people can benefit from my posts as much as I&#39;ve benefited from theirs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting</title>
      <link>https://using.tech/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://using.tech/consulting/</guid>
      <description>If you have a consulting opportunity that you think I may be interested in, please reach out to the email at the bottom of the page. I have significant experience in:
 Systems integration: Designing and maintaining frameworks for syncing services (Schoology, EducationCity, StudyIsland, Atlas Curriculum Management, NWEA MAP, etc.) with student information systems (Genesis). District Software Adoptions: District-wide subscription service rollouts (NWEA MAP, Schoology, Atlas Curriculum Management) including building the structures required for their continued support.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>